Privacy Policy
==============

version January 22nd, 2024

At Pimeyes (“**Pimeyes**”, “**We**”, “**Us**” and terms of similar meaning), we are committed to protecting privacy of our users (“**You**” or “**User**”) and ensuring the security of any personal data We receive from You. We understand the importance of privacy and have implemented policies and procedures to maintain the confidentiality of your personal data.

This Privacy Policy explains how We collect, use, and disclose Your personal data, and Your rights regarding that data. By using our services, You consent to the collection and use of Your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy (“**Privacy Policy**”), which applies to personal data We process and handle when You use Our products through Our website (the “**Services”**).

It is important to carefully read and understand both this Privacy Policy and the [Terms of Service](https://pimeyes.com/en/premium-terms) (the “**Term**”), as they create a legally binding agreement between You and Us. Therefore, please make sure to review them both thoroughly.

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, so We encourage You to review it regularly. If We make changes, We will notify You by email or by posting a notice on our website [https://pimeyes.com](https://pimeyes.com/) (“**Site**”).

However, notwithstanding the aforementioned clauses, all requests pertaining to personal data may be forwarded to Us via email at: [\[email protected\]](https://pimeyes.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). You are also able to fill out the forms as mentioned in this Privacy Policy.

We appreciate your trust in us and we will continue to work hard to earn it every day.

WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE PROCESS, FOR WHAT PURPOSE AND ON WHAT LEGAL BASIS?
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Before giving Your consent, we need you to understand what type of data we may collect:

### What we process:

**1\. Things you provide to us:**

* To access Our Services, you may need to create an account and voluntarily provide us with certain data like your email address and password.
* Some of Our services may require identity verification, and we may collect email addresses, full name, address, and photo, an anonymized scan of passport or ID, for this purpose.

PimEyes provides Users with the opportunity to exercise their specific rights in connection with the processing of personal data, such as the right to opt-out (“**opt-out**”) have their data completely deleted from the PimEyes system ([Opt-Our Request Form](https://pimeyes.com/en/opt-out-request-form)). The exercise of these rights necessitates that the User provide a photo of themselves, an anonymised scan of their identification document (where only their photo is shown and other data is covered), an email address, and a telephone number (to communicate in case of such need). The aforementioned data is processed for the express purpose of responding to a request, even when the legal provisions require the establishment of a request procedure, as well as for the purposes related to the establishment, exercise, or defence of legal claims.

Pimeyes also provides User with Takedown service (“**Takedown**”) as part of the PROtect and Advanced Plans, we at your behest and with your consent have to share with Your photo, signature, address, an anonymised scan of their identification document ([How to prepare and anonymize the scan of your document](https://pimeyes.com/en/tutorials/how-to-prepare-and-anonymize-the-scan-of-your-document)), an email address, and a telephone number (to communicate in case of such need). We have to share personal data provided by You with the aim of having photos selected by You removed from external websites.

* Your photo.

When you voluntarily use our services, you may choose to upload photos to our Site. We collect and store these photos in order to provide our services to you, in the manner and timeframe as described in this Privacy Policy.

We will never use your photos for any purpose other than providing our services to you, unless we obtain your explicit consent. We will never sell your photos to third parties, and we will only share them with trusted partners who help us provide our services as described in this Privacy Policy.

We take reasonable steps to protect your photos from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We use encryption to secure your photos while they are in transit and at rest, and We comply with all applicable privacy laws and regulations.

You have the right to access, correct, or delete your photos at any time, and you can contact us if you have any questions or concerns about our privacy practices.

**By uploading photos to our Site, you agree to the terms of this privacy policy and give us your consent to collect, use, and share your photos as described herein. If you do not agree to these terms, please refrain from uploading photo on our Site.**

* Payment data, such as your name surname and geographic location.

To ensure the secure processing of online payments for our Users, PimEyes engages the services of a reputable third-party entities (“**Entities**”), which acts as a merchant of records. To understand what personal data these Entities collect and store, please refer to the respective Entities’ terms and privacy policy. This Entities handle the personal data of Our Users in its own capacity, with the sole purpose of executing the payment process.

The merchant of records provides PimEyes with essential data regarding the status of the User's payment, such as the success or failure of the transaction, as well as the geographic location from which the payment was initiated. PimEyes then utilises this data to facilitate the registration of the payment and ultimately to provide the requested service to Our Users.

Entities in addition to facilitating transactions, also furnishes PimEyes with the vital data regarding User identification such as their full name and surname. These specific personal details pertaining to the User, are essential to PimEyes for the purpose of establishing, exercising, or defending their legal rights and interests. Furthermore, this data is also required for billing purposes, in order to accurately and effectively process payment transactions.

* If you communicate with us, for example through email or by filling out forms placed on Site, we may collect data that you provide, such as feedback, survey responses, or other submissions.

**2\. Data collected when you use our Services:**

* Data about how you use our services, such as your activity, search results, data usage, and duration of use.
    
* Data about the device you use to access our services, such as device type, browser type, and operating system.
    
* Data about the requests you make to our servers, such as what you request, when you request it, and where you came from.
    
* Data about your location, which we may collect using your device's GPS or your IP address.

**3\. Data collected in PimEyes’ index:**

PimEyes, akin to conventional search engines, provides a service to the User by utilising its unique index. Specifically, the search engine indexes "fingerprints" of faces found on the Internet with the sole purpose of facilitating future searches. PimEyes does not engage in targeted searches for any particular individual, but rather indexes images that are openly available on the Internet, along with corresponding data about their respective sources. Notably, PimEyes does not undertake any action to confirm the identities of the persons depicted in the indexed photos, whom this policy refers to as "unidentified entities."

In pursuit of creating an index that relies on publicly available sources, PimEyes processes the indexed data. The objective is to provide a high-quality service to Users in the future.

When presenting the search results, PimEyes employs a secure on-the-fly process, also known as a proxy, to download and display images from external websites. These images are stored for a temporary period not exceeding 30 calendar days and are instantaneously deleted upon being exhibited.

Data which is processed in the PimEyes index stems from sources that are publicly accessible. During the collection of such data, PimEyes abides by the distinct regulations of each website accessed by PimEyesBot web robots and only downloads data from sites which officially allow data scrapping.

PimEyes presents images from external websites, but the content exhibited therein is not within its purview. Nevertheless, PimEyes exerts every effort to cull explicit or pornographic content or have it obscured.

### Why we process:

Apart from the reasons described above, here are the reasons why We collect the data given in article 1 of this Privacy Policy.

* Providing, maintaining, troubleshooting, and supporting our services: We collect and use your data to fulfil our duty towards you and provide you with the best service possible.
    
* Communicating with users and prospective users: We use your data to respond to your requests and keep you informed about our services.
    
* Improving our services: We have a legitimate interest in improving and optimizing our services, so we may use your data to make necessary improvements.
    
* Developing new services: To better understand what new services users may want, we may use customer feedback.
    
* Legal compliance: We use your data as required by applicable law, legal process, or regulation. We also use your data to enforce our legal rights and resolve disputes. To learn more about how we share your data with third parties for legal compliance purposes, please refer to our privacy policy.
    
* Marketing and advertising our services: We use your data to personalize and enhance our advertising and marketing based on our legitimate interest in offering you services that may be of interest.
    
* Preventing harm or liability: To protect our customers and comply with legal obligations, we may use your data for security purposes and to prevent abuse and fraud.

### International Transfers:

We may collect Your personal data from transfer it to, and store and process it in Belize and other countries outside of where you live. Whenever we share information of EU Users outside the EU We make sure an adequate transfer mechanism is in place, personal data shared is in limited and specific cases, and We ensure a level of protection essentially equivalent to that guaranteed within the EU, and You are able to enforce Your data protection rights and effective legal remedies.

We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of our customers' personal information. As part of this commitment, We may collect Your personal data from transfer it to, and store and process it in Belize and other countries outside of where you live and where the personal data was collected.

We will take appropriate measures to ensure that your personal information receives adequate protection, including through the use of appropriate contractual clauses and other safeguards that comply with applicable data protection laws. These measures may include, but are not limited to, obtaining your explicit consent to the transfer of your personal information, or ensuring that the third-party recipient of your personal information is trusted third-party, with whom We have bilateral contractual obligations.

We may transfer personal information for the purposes of processing, storage, backup, or disaster recovery to Our service providers, including cloud providers, located in various countries around the world. We will only transfer Your personal information to these service providers if we have taken steps to ensure that your personal information will be adequately protected by the service provider.

We will also comply with all applicable laws and regulations related to the transfer of personal information across international borders, including, but not limited to, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

If You have any questions or concerns about Our international transfers of personal information, please contact Us. We will be happy to provide You with more information and address any concerns You may have.

VOLUNTARY DATA PROVIDING
------------------------

We understand that privacy is important to Our Users. We are committed to protecting Your personal data and being transparent about how we collect, use, and share that data. We want You to feel comfortable using Our services, and We believe that giving Your control over Your data is an important part of that.

When you use our services, it is your choice to provide Us with personal data such as your name, email address, face image or other identifying data. You do so voluntarily, and we will only collect data that is necessary for Us to provide Our services to You.

We may also collect certain data automatically when You use our services, such as your device type, IP address, and browsing history. This data helps us understand how Our services are being used and improve them over time. However, You have the option to disable certain types of data collection through your device settings.

By using our Services You agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and give us Your consent to collect, use, and share your personal data as described herein. You have the right to access, correct, or delete your personal data at any time, and you can contact us through the [contact form](https://pimeyes.com/en/contact-form) if you have any questions or concerns about Our privacy practices.

DOES PIMEYES SHARE PERSONAL DATA WITH THIRD PARTIES?
----------------------------------------------------

Generally, PimEyes is committed to protecting the personal data of its Users, except in cases where access to such data is necessary for the proper performance of services or for the execution of orders that You have entrusted to us. As such, We entrust this data to third-party service providers with whom We form exclusive agreements that guarantee of appropriate confidentiality and data processing terms and limit data sharing to the scope of what they are helping Us with.

We may share you data only if:

* You have given us instructions or consent to do so (including Takedown service).
    
* We may work with our affiliates, partners, and trusted third-party service providers to help us with certain aspects of our services such as processing customer payments, providing analytics, sales and customer support, delivering marketing and advertising content, and serving advertising content.
    
* We may use and share generic, non-identifying demographic data for regulatory compliance, research and analysis, our own marketing and advertising activities, and other legitimate business purposes.
    
* We will comply with legal process and the law. We may share your data if we are required to do so by applicable law, to comply with our legal obligations, to comply with legal process, and to respond to valid law enforcement requests relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity. If we share your data for these purposes, we limit the data shared to what is legally necessary, and challenge data requests that we believe are unlawful, overbroad, or otherwise invalid.
    
* If a substantial corporate transaction occurs, we may share the personal data we collect in connection with that transaction.
    
* We may share limited amounts of your data to enforce and administer our agreements with customers and users, to respond to claims asserted against us, and to protect against fraud and abuse against us, our affiliates, users, and others.

HOW LONG USERS’ PERSONAL DATA WILL BE STORED?
---------------------------------------------

We generally retain your personal data for as long as is needed to provide the services to You, or for as long as You have an account with us. We may also store personal data for the duration of the service, as well as for a period of time necessary to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims and for compliance with legal obligations.

* In regards to processing data only in response to Your inquiry, it is Our policy to delete the related personal data, as well as any contact forms sent, within a twelve month period after the response is made or the last contact with the individual is initiated. This time period helps us to analyse and improve Our Services and modify it according to your needs.
    
* Customer data: We will retain Your data for as long as You have an active account with us. After Your account is closed, we may retain your data for up to reasonable period of time not exceeding 30 calendar days to comply with legal requirements and for archival purposes.
    
* We will retain User’s search results for 30 calendar days after User performs the search.
    
* In case of opt-out, We will retain uploaded data for reasonable period of time (no more than 96 hours), which is needed to carry out your request.After opt-out is carried out the personal data is permanently removed from our system. We only keep a record of the request and the steps We took to respond to it, to meet our legal responsibilities.
    
* In case of Takedown, We will retain your personal data for as long as You have an active account with Us or You remove it from User panel. We will retain the form filled in by You ["Personal Data"](https://pimeyes.com/en/user/personal-details) forever, so that we can prove the basis of the relevant assignment requested by You.
    
* All facial images of Users not having account but given clear affirmative consent while agreeing on this Privacy Policy and Terms of Service, are securely stored for 48 hours after the User not having account sends the photo in order to process the search query.
    
* In the event of a breach of this Privacy Policy, Terms of Service, infringement of privacy regulations, for security, fraud and abuse prevention, to comply with legal or regulatory requirements we reserve the right to retain personal data for a reasonable period of time in order to take appropriate legal and administrative action.

When we no longer need to retain Your personal data or no longer have your consent to do so, we will immediately start the deletion in a secure and responsible manner. The full deletion process can take up to 30 calendar days..

You have right to access, correct, or delete your personal data, the right to object to processing, the right to restrict processing, and the right to data portability. To exercise your rights, please contact us at: [\[email protected\]](https://pimeyes.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Age Restrictions
----------------

Our Services are not intended for use by individuals under the age of eighteen (18), and therefore We do not intentionally collect Personal data from minors (under 18). If you are under the age of eighteen (18), please do not provide any Personal data to us unless you have the involvement and consent of a parent or legal guardian. In accordance with the GDPR, we do not offer services directly to children.

In the event that We discover We have unintentionally collected personal data from a minor (under 18) without appropriate consents, We may delete the data without prior notice. Depending on the country, parental consent may be necessary for processing the personal data of children under the age of 16. In these instances, those under 16 cannot use our services without the consent or authorization of their parent or legal guardian. If you suspect that a minor (under 18) has provided us with personal data without parental or guardian consent, please contact us.

Data Related to children
------------------------

We are committed to the highest standards of data privacy, especially when it comes to minors. We want to assure You that we do not collect, search, or permit the searching of data pertaining to minors. Recognizing the heightened sensitivity surrounding information related to minors, we have implemented stringent measures to ensure their protection. Our systems are designed to proactively identify and exclude any data associated with individuals below the under eighteen (18) or under sixteen (16) depending on applicable legislation. Our commitment extends to using every possible means to safeguard the well-being of children online and to uphold their rights to a safe and secure digital experience.

Furthermore, We are dedicated to the continuous improvement of our technological infrastructure to better identify and address any instances where searches or data related to minors may occur. We understand the evolving nature of digital landscapes and the need for constant attention in protecting the interests of minors. In line with this Privacy Policy, We are committed to utilizing advanced algorithms and monitoring mechanisms to detect and prevent any unauthorized access or usage involving minors. Should any such activity be identified, we pledge to intervene promptly through the ways as described in this Privacy Policy. Our ongoing commitment is not only to comply with legal requirements but to surpass them, ensuring a secure and responsible platform. We remain committed in our dedication to providing a safe and enriching online experience for the Users.

WEB BROWSER COOKIES
-------------------

Cookies are used by Us to provide a better user experience. For example, cookies can be used to remember Your login data, so you don't have to enter it every time you visit a website. Cookies makes it easier and faster to navigate a website and find the data you're looking for.

Cookies are also used for advertising purposes. We use cookies to track your browsing behavior and to create a profile of Your interests. This profile is then used to show you targeted advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to You. This means that You're less likely to see irrelevant or annoying ads and more likely to see ads that are relevant and useful to You.

Cookies are harmless bits of data that enhance your online experience by helping to remember your preferences. It's crucial to note that cookies themselves do not contain viruses or malware. Your privacy is important to Us, and We want to assure you that cookies are a common and safe tool used in online environments.

We value your consent, and you have the freedom to manage your cookie preferences. In your browser settings, you can decide whether to accept and reject them. Additionally, you have the option to delete cookies that are already stored. We believe in transparency, and we respect your choices. However, it's essential to be aware that opting to reject or delete cookies might impact your user experience on certain websites. We are committed to providing you with the information and tools you need to make informed decisions about your online privacy. You can modify Your cookie settings at any time, ensuring that you have control over your digital experience.

**By continuing to use the Site, you acknowledge and consent to the terms outlined regarding the use of cookies for personalized ads, understanding that your user experience may be tailored based on your preferences. Your continued engagement serves as an indication of Your acceptance of these terms and Your consent for Us to utilize Your personal data for advertising purposes.**

GOOGLE SERVICES
---------------

PimEyes employs Google Analytics, a sophisticated web service that leverages data collected from “cookies” to analyse website traffic. This service furnishes PimEyes with comprehensive reports on the SIte’s activity, the usage patterns of its users, and additional internet usage services. Google Analytics is instrumental in facilitating ongoing improvement of the Site and ensuring that its services align with the needs and expectations of users. Users can exercise their option to disable Google Analytics services by downloading the Google plugin available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

To authenticate human access to the Site and discern automated ones, PimEyes utilises Google's reCAPTCHA system - a cutting-edge risk analysis engine. This technology typically requires users to either rewrite letters or numbers or identify appropriate images. Additional details regarding Google Analytics and reCAPTCHA, including the processing of user data, are available in the Google Privacy Policy and Google Terms of Service, which apply to both Google services.

HOW PIMEYES SAFEGUARDS ITS SERVICES AND PROTECTS YOUR DATA
----------------------------------------------------------

We take data privacy seriously and have implemented various technical and organizational measures to ensure that We are in full compliance with applicable data protection laws and regulations. We utilise suitable data gathering, storage and processing practices and safety safeguards to thwart unauthorised access, modification, revelation or destruction of User's personal data, username, password, transaction data and data stored on the Site. All sensitive and private data exchanges between the Site and its Users occur through an SSL secured communication channel, ensuring a professional level of security.

Additionally, a variety of organisational and technical measures are in place to prevent misuse of our Services and violation of privacy regulations. These measures include, but are not limited to:

### 1\. “No harm” policy:

We are committed to protecting Your personal data and strive to maintain its confidentiality, integrity, and availability. We follow industry best practices to protect personal data from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, and to prevent the loss, misuse, or theft of personal data.

We have implemented technical, physical, and administrative safeguards to protect Your personal data, including but not limited to encryption, access controls, and regular security testing. We also limit access to personal data to authorized personnel who have a legitimate business need to access it.

We do not sell or rent personal data to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

We only retain personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected, or as required by law.

We recognize that no security measures can provide absolute protection against all threats, and We cannot guarantee the security of Your personal data. However, We are committed to promptly notifying you in the event of a data breach that affects Your personal data and taking appropriate measures to mitigate the impact of such a breach.

We believe in Our responsibility to minimize the risk of harm to individuals in the event of a data breach or other privacy-related incident. We have implemented a "no harm" policy, which means that in the event of a data breach or other privacy-related incident, We will take all necessary steps to minimize the risk of harm to affected individuals. This may include providing free credit monitoring services or other remedial measures as necessary.

If you believe that Your personal data has been compromised or that We have violated your privacy rights in any way, please contact us immediately. We will promptly investigate Your concerns and take appropriate action to address them.

### 2\. Security Policy:

**2.1 Your data is safe with Our employees:**

All support workers, including customer support specialists, PROtect team specialists, and data security officers are obliged to protect any personal data or stories received from You during their professional activity.

The employees attending to sensitive cases of the Users will be of the same gender as the User, to ensure an appropriate and professional environment.

Besides providing legal and technical training for employees who interact directly with users, additional training in the management of sensitive/problematic communications (e.g. prevention of suicide and behavioural psychology) is also offered in a professional manner.

Candidates with a degree or training in applied psychology are given preferential consideration, when recruiting for customer support personnel and PROtect team members in a professional manner.

**2.2 Data security:**

We employ technical and organizational measures to protect against unauthorized or unlawful processing of personal data and against accidental loss, destruction, or damage.

Regular reviews: We regularly review and update our privacy and security practices to ensure that they remain up-to-date and effective.

We believe that these measures demonstrate Our commitment to protecting the privacy and security of personal data and allow Us to offer Our services in full compliance with applicable data protection laws and regulations.

In order to minimise the risks of infringing copyright regulations, to enforce a policy of only scraping data from websites, which officially grant such permission.

We purposefully avoid targeting all known social media and social networking platforms. Including professional networks on search engines and crawlers.

To dissuade and prohibit any unauthorised, external use of its services and products, We enforce a policy of no API access for either individuals or entities.

**2.3 We have developed and implemented an AI-based multi-step monitoring system, which helps us to detect:**

Frequency of product usage - simultaneous and concurrent searches are intercepted and prevented in order to avert the exploitation of shared accounts, bots, or other unauthorised individuals.

Detect any unauthorised searches – any User whose search goes against our Privacy Policy, Terms of Service or applicable law will be warned and in case of repeat blocked. You must totally understand that You are solely responsible for any search (including illegal ones) and in case of legal breach we reserve right to inform government authorities about such breach, as it is envisaged in this Privacy Policy.

**2.4 No service available for sanctioned countries or individuals:**

We do not provide Our services to individuals or entities located in or subject to sanctions by the United States, the European Union, the United Kingdom or other applicable laws and regulations.

We also do not provide Our services to individuals or entities on the U.S. Department of Commerce's Denied Persons List, Entity List, or Unverified List, the U.S. Department of Treasury's Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons List, the European Union's Consolidated List of Persons, Groups, and Entities Subject to EU Financial Sanctions, or the United Kingdom's Consolidated List of Financial Sanctions Targets, or any other applicable lists of sanctioned or restricted parties.

If We become aware that an individual or entity is located in or subject to sanctions by the United States, the European Union, the United Kingdom, or other applicable laws and regulations, or is listed on any applicable sanctions or restricted party lists, We reserve the right to take any actions We deem necessary, including but not limited to denying access to our services or terminating any existing agreements or relationships.

We take our legal and regulatory obligations seriously and strive to ensure that Our services are provided in full compliance with applicable laws and regulations. We encourage all Users to comply with all applicable laws and regulations and to seek legal advice if they have any questions or concerns about their legal obligations.

SPECIFIC NOTICES TO ILLINOIS RESIDENTS
--------------------------------------

PimEyes does not offer any services in Illinois or for Illinois residents. PimEyes has implemented all possible technical measures to block all data that can be reasonably linked with Illinois or Illinois residents (“**Illinois Data**”), both at the stage of collecting data from publicly available sources as well as when provided by the data subjects or from a source other than the data subject.

Notwithstanding the above, any data subject to whom the Illinois Biometric Data Privacy Act (“**BIPA**”) applies, is entitled to exercise the opt-out right to have any and all of their data removed from the PimEyes system. The opt-out form is available here: [opt-out form](https://pimeyes.com/en/opt-out-request-form).

PimEyes may process Illinois Data only in rare cases, i.e., to the extent of defending against legal claims or to satisfy the opt-out request. Such data is stored in accordance with this Privacy Policy, including the retention periods, provided that, based on BIPA the aforementioned data is always destroyed no later than when the initial purpose for collecting them has been satisfied or within 3 years of the data subject’s last interaction with PimEyes, whichever occurs first.

SPECIFIC NOTICES TO NEVADA RESIDENTS
------------------------------------

PimEyes is conscious of the responsibility it has under Nevada Statute Chapter 603A - Security and Privacy of an individual's data. We only deliver search results to the Users and have no intentions of selling personal data in the future. If a resident of Nevada doesn't wish to be featured in search results, they can submit a request to exercise their opt-out right to have their data removed from the PimEyes system. The opt-out form can be accessed here: [opt-out form](https://pimeyes.com/en/opt-out-request-form).

SPECIFIC NOTICES TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS
----------------------------------------

As a California resident, it is important to note that certain legal guidelines, as well as extra consumer rights, are provided by the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”). It is essential for individuals to abide by these regulations for the protection of their personal data.

_Please note, that according to the CCPA:_

“Personal data” means data that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or household, for example real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, social security number, driver’s license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers, but also biometric data.

A California resident, who is a natural person is referred to as a "Consumer".

A "Household" is a collective, identified by their residential address, of Consumers who reside together and make use of shared devices or services.

Consumer has the following additional rights regarding the Personal data:

### 1\. Upon a verifiable consumer request :

**a)** A Consumer has the right, to know what Personal Data is being collected by PimEyes. In order to exercise this right, a Consumer must make a verifiable request and, upon successfully verifying the request, PimEyes will provide the Consumer with the relevant data :

• Categories of Personal data PimEyes has collected about that Consumer,

• Categories of sources from which the Personal data is collected,

• Business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling, or sharing Personal data,

• Categories of third parties to whom PimEyes discloses Personal data,

• Specific pieces of Personal data PimEyes has collected about that specific Consumer.

_The data supplied by PimEyes will be restricted to the past twelve months._

**b)** Right to access Personal data;

In order to fulfil this obligation, the Consumer should submit a verifiable request and upon successful verification, PimEyes will promptly disclose and provide the Personal data requested, at no charge to the Consumer. The data may be delivered by mail or electronically and if provided electronically, the data shall be in a portable and to the extent technically feasible, readily useable format, that allows the Consumer to transmit this data to another entity, without hindrance.

**c)** Right to request the deletion of Personal data;

To fulfil the right for consumers to delete some or all of their Personal data, after verification of the request, PimEyes will delete the data, with allowances for any exceptions that result from the California Consumer Privacy Act. If an exception applies, FRA informs you about it in writing.

According to CCPA “Verifiable Consumer Request” is a request, that is made by a Consumer, by a Consumer on behalf of the Consumer’s minor child, by a natural person or a person registered with the Secretary of State. Authorised by the Consumer, to act on the Consumer’s behalf, or by a person who has power of attorney or is acting as a conservator for the Consumer, and that PimEyes can verify, using commercially reasonable methods.

PimEyes shall provide the necessary data to a Consumer without any cost within 45 days of effectively receiving a Verifiable Consumer Request. On legitimate grounds, an extension of 45 more days can be allowed with the Consumer being duly notified of the delay during the initial 45-day period. When there is a need to address the complexity and quantity of the requests, the duration to respond to any Verified Consumer Request could potentially be extended by a further 90 days. PimEyes will advise the Consumer of such an expansion and the reasons for such a postponement within 45 days of receipt of the request, all in a professional manner.

**Verifiable Consumer Request :**

* To ensure accurate identification of the Consumer, it is necessary to collect the Consumer's e-mail address, a face photo, and in the event a request is submitted to access their data, a copy of the Consumer's identity document with the appropriate photo.
    
* If you are representing a Consumer, it is in your best interest to provide PimEyes with appropriate documentation verifying your authority to act on behalf of the Consumer. PimEyes has the right to request authorisation from the Consumer before proceeding.
    
* If you act as a household, PimEyes will require all Consumers constituting the household to submit the request.

Verifiable Consumer Request can be made by sending an email containing, respectively, all necessary elements described above to the following email address: [\[email protected\]](https://pimeyes.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### 2\. Right to opt-out the sale of Personal data.

CCPA provides the Consumers with a right to opt-out the sale of Personal data. PimEyes provides the Users only with the search results, i.e., does not sell and declares that it does not intend to sell Personal data in the future. However, if you don’t want to appear in search results, you have a right to submit a request to exercise the opt-out right to have any and all of your data removed from the PimEyes system. The opt-out form is available here: [opt-out form](https://pimeyes.com/en/opt-out-request-form).

### 3\. Right to non-discrimination,

PimEyes does not discriminate against a Consumer, because the Consumer exercised any of the Consumer’s rights under CCPA, including, but not limited to, by:

• Denying goods or services to the Consumer.

• Charging different prices or rates for goods or services, including through the use of discounts or other benefits or imposing penalties.

• Providing different level or quality of goods or services to the Consumer

• The Consumer may receive a differing cost or rate for the same goods or services, or they may receive a different quality or standard of them.

### 4\. Consumers have the right to request the removal of all their data from the PimEyes system, by filling out [opt-out form](https://pimeyes.com/en/opt-out-request-form).

PimEyes recognises its responsibility as outlined in the California Code of Civil Procedure (CIV § 1798.83) and asserts that they do not transfer or disclose Personal details to third parties for marketing orders. Therefore, PimEyes does not have any specific procedure for processing requests in relation to these matters.

COPYRIGHTS
----------

All materials contained on Site, including text, graphics, icons, images, and software, are Our property. You may access and use the materials on this website solely for Your personal, non-commercial use. Any reproduction, distribution, modification, or publication of the materials on this website without our prior written permission is strictly prohibited.

We respect the intellectual property rights of others and expect You to do the same. If You believe that your work has been copied in a way that constitutes copyright infringement, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://pimeyes.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). In Your message, please provide a description of the copyrighted work that You claim has been infringed, a description of the location on Our website where the infringing material is located, your contact information, and a statement that you have a good-faith belief that the disputed use is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law.

We reserve the right to remove any content that is alleged to infringe the copyright of another party without prior notice, at Our sole discretion, and without liability to You or any other party.

DMCA NOTIFICATION
-----------------

PimEyes responds to all notifications of copyright infringement in accordance with the DMCA. Please, be advised, that you can send an effective notification, only if you are the copyright owner. Person authorised to act on behalf of the copyright owner or a person authorised to act under any exclusive right, according to DMCA.

In accordance with Section 512(c)(3)(A) of Title 17 of the DMCA, a notification must be made in writing and must include the following :

**I)** The written or electronic authorisation of a person, whose authority has been approved by the proprietor of a unique right which is supposedly violated.

**II)** Identification of the copyrighted work, claimed to have been infringed or, if multiple copyrighted works at a single online site are covered by a single notification, a representative list of such works at that site.

**III)** Details of the material, that is claimed to be infringing or subject to infringing activity and allows it to be located, thus enabling PimEyes to remove or disable access to it.

**IV)** Reasonably sufficient data, to permit PimEyes contacting the complaining party, such as an address, telephone number and if available, an electronic mail address at which the complaining party may be contacted.

**V)** Statement, that the complaining party has a good faith, belief, that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorised by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law.

**VI)** Statement, that the data in the notification is accurate and that the complaining party is authorised under the penalty of perjury, to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed.

DMCA notification can be made by filling in a DMCA Request Form available under [this link](https://pimeyes.com/en/dmca-request-form).

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
------------------------------

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time and will update the "Last revised" date at the top of this page to reflect the most recent version. It is Your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Your continued use of Our services after any modifications to the Privacy Policy will constitute Your acceptance of such changes.

CONTACTING PIMEYES
------------------

We are committed to maintaining the accuracy, confidentiality, and security of Your personal data. If You have any questions or concerns about Our privacy practices, or if You would like to request access to, correction, or deletion of your personal data, please contact Us. We will respond to your inquiry as soon as possible.

Please note that we may need to verify your identity before fulfilling certain requests, such as providing access to Your personal data. We will make reasonable efforts to respond to your request within the timeframes required by law.

It's important to ensure that the contact information provided is up-to-date and that someone is responsible for responding to inquiries and complaints promptly.

### Contact information:

PimEyes [here](https://pimeyes.com/en/contact-form), or to the Carribex LTD: New Horizon Building, Ground Floor, 3 1/2 Miles Philip S.W. Goldson Highway, Belize City.

**PimEyes**

### How we operate

### Searching for public information only

We search only the open web and sites that allow crawling their data. That means we do not search social media, private accounts, or look for any information that is available only for registered users.

### Searching, not surveilling

We are a self-investigative tool that allows people to search for publicly available information about themselves. PimEyes is not intended for the surveillance of others and is not designed for that purpose.

### Fighting against scammers

We help people find and identify crimes directed against them like catfishing, nonconsensual pornography, or identity thefts. We also give our users the tools to take action against their abusers.

### Providing links, not controlling them

We provide links to external websites, however, we are not responsible for the content presented on them. By delivering links in the search results we do not endorse these external websites or their practices.

© 2017 - 2024 PimEyes  v17.4.11
